How do you pay for your coffee?
你怎样付款买咖啡呢？
Is it with change?
是用零钱吗？
I use my tap-and-go card.
我用我的感应式支付卡。
I don't even need to enter my PIN number or a signature to authorise payment.
我甚至不需要输入个人密码或签名来授权付款。
It's quicker and everybody in the queue is happy.
这样更快，而且排队的每个人都很高兴。
Contactless payments are gaining popularity.
非接触式支付越来越受欢迎。
Those concerned about security will be pleased to know that the amount of money you can spend in one go is limited - in the UK it's currently £30.
那些担心安全问题的人会很高兴知道，你一次可以消费的金额是有限制的——在英国，目前是30英镑。
But if the card is used a few times in a row, a PIN number will be needed.
但如果这张卡连续使用几次，就需要输入个人密码了。
If a thief gets hold of your card and goes on a spending spree, your bank covers you against fraud.
如果小偷拿到了你的卡并进行疯狂消费，你的银行会为你承担欺诈造成的损失。
Whereas, if someone steals your banknotes, that's your bad luck!
然而，如果有人偷了你的纸币，那你就倒霉了！
For those who are always forgetting where they put their cards, there's a new solution: wearable tech: clothing and accessories that have integrated electronic technology.
对于那些总是忘记把卡放在哪里的人来说，有一个新的解决方案：可穿戴技术，即集成了电子技术的服装和配饰。
Kenneth Cukier, an economist and technology expert, says: "You can simply take any wireless card and the chip from it that your bank might issue you with, and you can put it in a coat.
经济学家兼技术专家肯尼斯·库基尔说：“你可以简单地取出银行发给你的任何一张无线卡及其芯片，然后把它放进一件外套里。
When you want to make a payment just wave your arm in front of the terminal and leave the coffee shop with your latte.
当你想付款时，只需在终端机前面挥一挥手臂，然后就可以拿着你的拿铁离开咖啡店了。
This is intended for people who don't want to take their card out of their wallet, use their phone or their watch."
这是为那些不想从钱包里拿出卡，也不想用手机或手表付款的人设计的。”
Good, isn't it?
很棒，不是吗？
And new ways of spending money are not stopping there.
而且新的支付方式还不止于此。
The future is all about biometrics.
未来是生物识别技术的天下。
Very convenient if you are at the beach or a festival - there's a new system in development which will make it possible to read the unique maps of veins under the surface of your finger, and use them to authenticate payments - or prove that it's you making the payments.
如果你在海滩或参加节日活动，这会非常方便——有一种正在开发的新系统，它将能够读取你手指表面下独特的静脉纹路图，并利用它们来验证付款，也就是证明是你在进行付款。
You just need to remember which finger you registered with.
你只需要记住你是用哪根手指注册的就行了。
So spending money is becoming easier all the time.
所以花钱总是变得越来越容易了。
And the temptation to buy more stuff increases.
而且购买更多东西的诱惑也增加了。
But it's worth bearing in mind that earning the money in the first place will still require the same effort.
但值得注意的是，首先要赚到钱，这仍然需要付出同样的努力。
Back to work then!
那就回去工作吧！